# **Muhammad Burhan Ahmad**

Dubai, UAE

**E:** <u>muhdburh@gmail.com</u> **M:** +971521566568

www.linkedin.com/in/burhan066 https://burhanahmad02.github.io/

#### **PROFILE**

As a passionate game developer with over two years of experience, I have developed and deployed more than 10 games. I have worked with teams of up to 15 people, managing all aspects of the game development process, from concept to launch. With a strong background in programming, design, and project management, I am committed to creating engaging and immersive game experiences that captivate players. I am eager to continue advancing my knowledge of AI algorithms and their application in game development, with a goal of achieving even greater success in the gaming industry.

# **EDUCATION**

Comsats University Islamabad, Pakistan

**BSc Computer Science** 

2017-2021

**TECH SKILLS & PROJECTS** 

Skills: Unity 3D, C#, Trello, Slack, Source Control, Doxygen

**Artificial Intelligence:** Computer Vision, Image Processing, Pattern recognition, Machine learning, Image Labelling, Testing, Creating Datasets

**Soft-Skills:** Leadership, Team-management, Collaborative, Cooperative, Analytical thinking, Team Player

**PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE** 

# Game Ever Studio Pvt. Ltd Dubai, UAE Unity Game Developer

April 2022 – Present

### Five Ocean 2D

- Implemented mechanics and physics-based Submarine, resulting in a more realistic and engaging gameplay experience
- Built engaging gameplay with AI system detecting hidden enemies and AI manager spawning skilled enemies with unique patrol routes and increasing accuracy over time.
  Demonstrated expertise in game design and programming
- Coded a Radar System which was responsible for detecting enemies with each clockwise rotation of its sweep, resulting in a 30% increase in player engagement

## FPS Game

- Crafted seamless gameplay with unique First-Person characters, reactive Enemy Al system, and engaging controls. Translated complex game concepts into an immersive experience
- Overall UI implementation and UI animation

#### • FPS Sci-fi Game

- Masterfully blended technical and artistic skills to design immersive VFX, sound, and shader effects for environments and weapons
- Crafted dynamic, captivating death animations for the player using Cine-machine virtual camera, showcasing a deep understanding of both animation and programming
- Compressed sound and sprite sizes to achieve blazing-fast player experience, optimized with 30mb build size reduction
- Introduced scalable Achievement system with scriptable objects, elevating player

experience. Demonstrated exceptional technical and creative skills

# • Sniper 3D FPS Game

- Devised and developed an Upgrade system for the attachments of the sniper rifles
- Target shooting level, where player can practice their aim and accuracy

# Viral Mobi Tech Pvt. Ltd Islamabad, Pakistan Game Developer Jan 2022 – April 2022

- Draw Bridge 2D
  - Established mechanics and physics-based vehicle
  - Utilized line renderer to draw a path with colliders and physics

### Spartans Global Pvt. Ltd Islamabad, Pakistan Game Dev Trainee Dec 2020 – Dec 2021

- Santa Pin-pull 2D SGPL Games
  - Leveraged Addressable for optimization of memory for 120 levels
  - Diversified the purchasable and rewarded gifts in the Shop by implementing JSON
- Rush To Crush SGPL Games Unity Game Developer
  - Enacted a bike based on mechanics, physics, and 2D ragdoll physics
  - Setup architecture to shift to scriptable objects
  - Introduced a shared biker rig, for custom animation
- Fashion Makeover SGPL Games Unity Game Developer
  - Designed and implemented architecture using scriptable objects
  - Optimized addressable implementation for scalable item database
  - Collaborated and guided Art and Design teams to ensure the best visuals and performance. Moreover, co-ordinated all core game mechanics

Potato Knights Pvt. Ltd Islamabad, Pakistan Intern (Game Dev) Jan 2020 – April 2020 EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES & AWARDS

## Awards:

- Fast University (Nuces):
  - Nascon-18 participated in Dota2, Nascon-18 participated in FIFA, Nascon-17 participated in Tekken-7 Fast University
- University of Engineering and Technology:
  - Tech-salvo 18 winner for Dota2 UET
- Comecs-18 runner up for Call of duty 4 Comsats University Islamabad

### Community meetups:

- Attended a One-day workshop on soft skills and Personality Development in Comsats University Islamabad
- Attended a One-day workshop on Linked-In in Comsats University Islamabad
- Attended a One-day workshop on C# programming skills in Comsats University Islamabad